Her game. Her rules.
Challengers is a drama, romance film directed by Luca Guadagnino.
Tennis player turned coach Tashi has taken her husband, Art, and
transformed him into a world-famous Major champion.
To jolt him out of his recent losing streak, she signs him up for a "Challenger" event — close to the lowest level of pro
tournament — where he finds himself standing across the net from his former best friend and Tashi's former boyfriend.
Tashi Donaldson, played by Zendaya.
Art Donaldson, played by Mike Faist.
Patrick Zweig, played by Josh O'Connor.
Umpire (New Rochelle Final), played by Darnell Appling.
Art's Physiotherapist, played by Bryan Doo.
Art's Security Guard, played by Shane T Harris.
Challengers is a 2024 American romantic sports film directed by
Luca Guadagnino and written by Justin Kuritzkes.
It follows the love triangle among an injured tennis star-turned-coach (Zendaya), her low-circuit tennis player ex-boyfriend (Josh O'Connor), and her tennis
champion husband (Mike Faist) across 13 years of their relationship, culminating in the match between the two men on the ATP Challenger Tour.
Kuritzkes' screenplay was acquired by MGM in February 2022, with the main cast and Guadagnino being hired shortly after; Zendaya,
O'Connor, and Faist trained for months with former tennis player and coach Brad Gilbert to prepare for their roles.
Principal photography ran from May to June 2022, primarily in Boston.
Sayombhu Mukdeeprom, who previously worked with Guadagnino on Call Me by Your
Name (2017) and Suspiria (2018), served as cinematographer.
Delayed from an initial September 2023 release in response to the 2023 SAG-AFTRA strike, Challengers premiered in Sydney on
March 26, 2024, and was theatrically released in the United States by Amazon MGM Studios one month later.
It grossed $96 million worldwide and received critical acclaim.
Among the film's accolades were four nominations at the 82nd Golden Globe Awards (including
Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy), where it won Best Original Score.
The film explores themes of infidelity, husband wife
relationship, love triangle, sports, tennis.
The tone is emotional.